Profile

I'm a nonprofit professional with experience in a spectrum of different roles. I have a passion for data and maintaining institutional knowledge. All aspects of data fascinate me, from the nuts and bolts of data wrangling and combining disparate information, to the ability to uncover insights and tell stories.

Skills

Data analysis, Python, PostgreSQL, Excel, Tableau, Power BI, inventory management, process creation and implementation, HTML, Wordpress, GIS, Spanish (professional level), Salesforce

Data Experience

Nashville Software School | Data Analyst

July 2021 - Present

NASHVILLE, TN

- Capstone: (ongoing) Gathering data for the end goal of mapping drug cartel violence in Mexico in relation to resource extraction and US funding of the drug war.
- Nashville Python Projects (Python): (ongoing) Created different maps and dataframes for the purpose of pulling insights from the data on Nashville's open data portal. Among these included assessing the zip codes where people are the happiest with Nashville's services, and mapping scooter and bus stop data for the purpose of analyzing last mile transportation.
- App Store Project (PostgreSQL): Built a query with PostgreSQL that joined the disparate data of the Apple app store and the Android app store with CTEs and subqueries. Strategized how best to combine columns when apps were in both stores and the best way to deal with "NaN" values when they were only in one store. In analyzing the data, identified the difference in engagement between an app that is free and an app that costs money. Created a unit chart visualization to show that for every 283 installs of a free app, there is one install for a paid app. Used this insight to promote the hypothesis that free apps are better for generating advertising and in-app purchasing revenue
- Lahman Baseball Project (PostgreSQL): Joined tables with PostgreSQL in order to pull out information to answer particular questions about baseball statistics with the Lahman Baseball dataset. The challenge with this dataset was figuring out the best way to get information from tables that weren't linked by a primary key, and what joins were needed
- Nashville Cemetery Project (Excel): Cleaned and organized data with Excel for the purpose of pulling out insights for a promotional brochure. Identified outliers in the data and researched the history behind them, uncovering newspaper clippings and taking a true crime angle as a way to drum up interest
- Power BI: Created a dashboard that utilized the Central Park Squirrel Census data to show squirrel sightings and actions by hectare. Identified that the hectares where squirrels were most likely to congregate were wooded but adjacent to places where people gathered

Experience

American Civil Liberties Union of Tennessee | Operations Manager

Aug 2018 - Present

NASHVILLE, TN

- Manage organization finances, generating budget reports in excel and working in Quickbooks
- Use Salesforce daily, maintaining donor data. Meet with ACLU National departments to discuss ways to improve workflow and processes for affiliate offices
- Set up and administrate our volunteer database in EveryAction, bringing together disparate data from different platforms to centralize the information of hundreds of volunteers
- Regularly evaluate organization processes to determine ways to improve efficiency and bring down costs

Southern Migrant Legal Services | Outreach Paralegal

May 2014 - Jul 2018

NASHVILLE, TN

Regularly downloaded data from a government database tracking H2-A visas to organize and carried out 6-10 trips per season to
visit approximately 200 farms. Spoke with farmworkers during these visits, giving know-your-rights presentations and
conducting fact finding missions. Wrote and filed each follow up report, accompanying spreadsheet, and map to preserve
institutional knowledge

- Opened approximately 125 intakes, communicating legal advice on behalf of the lawyers and seeing each case to its conclusion, using a proprietary database to track each one
- Provided litigation support in the form of administrative tasks, fact finding, investigation of pay records, securing documents, writing case memos, and interviewing clients
- Participated in settlement negotiations on behalf of clients

Asociación Educativa y Cultural El Arte Sano | English Teacher

Sep 2011 - Feb 2014

URUBAMBA, PERU

- Taught classes to native Spanish speakers at the basic, intermediate and advanced level
- Reworked the Basic 1 level curriculum with improved material, organizing it to facilitate ease of teaching and learning
- Created a materials resource accessible through Dropbox for the teachers and a new website using Wordpress, CSS and HTML

MicroAid International | Assistant Project Manager

Dec 2012 - Aug 2013

URUBAMBA, PERU

- Facilitated the meetings that brought about MicroAid's home construction project in Peru, making the contacts necessary and interviewing the beneficiary family
- Translated on the construction site daily between the Spanish speaking workers and MicroAid's English speaking director
- Assessed MicroAid's use of social media and blogging, improving its Facebook presence to better communicate with donors
- Recommended a number of changes to make website more intuitive and user friendly

Helpers for Domestic Helpers | Legal Advocate and Caseworker

Jun 2010 - Jul 2010

HONG KONG, CHINA

- Interviewed clients and took legal action in accordance with Hong Kong's legal procedures including not receiving the agreed upon salary from employers, wrongful firing cases and abusive situations
- Opened and tracked approximately 100 cases through legal stages
- Escorted and provided advice to domestic helpers during mediation and court hearings, three of whom received settlements

MADRE | Program Intern Jun 2009 - Aug 2009

NEW YORK, NY

- Collaborated in the writing of a report to raise funds for a project to bring a potable, sustainable water source to Nicaragua's North Atlantic coast; detailed the technology that would be used and how the project would proceed if funds were secured.
- Worked on a project that aimed to equip midwives in Palestine with supplies that would allow Palestinian women to give birth at home to prevent being detained at Isreali checkpoints. Filled out a spreadsheet consisting of the materials that would be needed with description and average cost.

Book Revue | Inventory Manager

May 2007- Dec 2009

HUNTINGTON, NY

Mar 2002 - Mar 2006

- Oversaw all aspects of inventory, including two different database systems, shipping, returns and ordering, established and maintained processes and served as a liaison with vendors
- Wrote a procedures manual to standardize and increase efficiency of all positions pertaining to inventory management. Initiated the creation and implementation of a variety of new procedures to standardize operations
- Developed a tracking system to mitigate lost shipments and the lack of prioritization in processing. Increased efficiency, insured popular books were available for sale on the release date and allowed staff to get up-to-the-moment status on any shipment
- Managed a database containing hundreds of vendors, publishers, clients and purchase orders
- Coordinated the move of the annex and warehouse. Organized approximately 5,000 books, insuring their safe move and categorization, delegating tasks to a staff of three. Prepared the store for a large new section to showcase a select amount
- Trained and supervised numerous employees to fill a variety of support positions throughout the store

Education

Nashville Software School | Data Analytics, Certification

Anticipated Jan 2021

NASHVILLE, TN

The New School | M.A. in International Affairs | Concentration in Governance and Rights

May 2011

NEW YORK, NY

Stony Brook University | B.A. in Cultural Anthropology

Dec 2007

STONY BROOK, NY